WHEN LIFE GIVES YOU TANGERINES
The Bu family owns
six out of ten boats in Dodong-ri.
Eight out of ten people in this town
work with them.
Gwan-sik is screwed.
It's not just Sang-gil. It's all of them.
His brother is village chief
and an even bigger asshat.
You know how island people get.
Bunch of little tyrants.
Ah.
What happened?
He wouldn't hire you again?
He blamed the economy.
As if the economy
ever stopped anyone from fishing.
Just go home!
Hey.
I hear they're building a road
around Hallasan Mountain.
Tell him to find a job there.
Whether it's in the field or in a boat,
a paycheck's a paycheck.
Conches for sale!
Top quality! Haenyeocaught!
We have conches, extra-fresh.
Meongge as well!
Poor boy. He's always the first
to arrive every morning.
He says it's his only chance
to get a spot on a boat.
Gwan-sik has to be first to even
get a chance to be considered for it.
It's not fair.
He has it a lot harder than the others.
What about working on land?
How does that sit with him?
He doesn't talk much. He's a quiet guy.
No wonder he doesn't like it.
A man of the sea
will always yearn for the sea.
Good Lord.
What is it this time?
What have they done to your arm?
I just don't have the skill set,
I guess, so…
Did they tell you not to come back?
Poor boy.
Why did he bother to fix
a perfectly good roof?
He should've just taken a break.
He was wilting away.
What else could happen to
a hard-working man who couldn't find work?
He made all these already?
We had three days to work on them.
Mom once said
that the leftover cabbages in the field
looked less wilted
than Dad lying on his side.
DODONG-RI VARIETY SHOP
Lie down. I've already started the rice.
Go easy on yourself.
Take it slow.
You're not a plow ox.
You've been selling fish
since you were nine,
and you're allowed to rest for once.
Think of this as a vacation.
I've never had one.
It feels strange.
Very strange.
Hey, you deserve a break more than anyone.
There's no law against
enjoying yourself, is there?
If I do that,
our family of four will starve.
It's simple.
If I work for one day,
we can live for one day.
I just wish finding it…
was that simple.
Why worry about starving?
I'll earn the money if we are short.
Coming from the bookworm
who couldn't sell a cabbage
to save her life?
Standing before the empty rice jar,
Mom remembered the smile she saw
so often on her own mother's face.
She remembered how her mother
forced herself to wear that smile
if it meant she could sell another conch.
Excuse me, uh,
we're out of rice.
Could I borrow--
I don't understand
what you're saying, girl.
What are you complaining about?
There's plenty of folks worse off.
It must have looked
exactly like the smile I remember
on Mom's young face.
It must have been forced just the same.
I swear, those ladies
always rip off your dad.
They charge a thousand won more.
Wow, haggling over 1,000 won?
You really are a mom.
What?
It's funny, is all.
When I was younger,
I couldn't even sell a cabbage
to save my life.
Seriously?
I was such
a shy little bookworm back then.
Whenever I sold cabbages
in my school uniform,
I held my book up this close to my face.
I was so embarrassed.
You were cool.
What happened?
I learned what things in life
are actually worth being ashamed of.
For example,
the sound of three growling stomachs
of your family in the night.
It's the sound of them going hungry.
There's nothing more embarrassing
than that.
Back then, I was so inexperienced.
For some reason,
it all felt so humiliating and pathetic.
There were many times
when I wanted to give up on life.
Say something already.
Nothing will get fixed
if you just sit there.
You wanna borrow our money?
What's the use
of trying to keep your pride?
If you can't say anything,
why bother coming here at all?
Well? What have you come for, kid?
Ae-sun, you don't live here anymore.
You live with them.
You should be asking his family for help.
Why come here
with that long face of yours?
I thought you could
care for yourself like your mother,
but you're as hopeless as your father.
You can't make ends meet?
And what if she can't?
We don't have any land left to sell.
You must really be desperate to come here,
but we're buried in debt ourselves.
Marriage was supposed to
make your life better.
Okay, fine, just give her the ring.
Damn it.
Oh my.
You don't have food to feed your child,
and you're too proud to beg?
You are still a little girl.
Honey.
Hmm?
All I want
is to get old as fast as I can.
Why?
Because
I always assumed when I was a grown-up,
I'd know how to manage problems
and tough issues.
Just like Auntie Gyeong-ja.
Even if creditors invaded the house,
I thought every adult would be fine.
I thought that when you grow up…
you would grow callouses
on your heart to withstand fire.
Here we are still getting burned.
It just burns us,
and it always hurts.
I can't be the only one.
Is everyone else
growing up just fine, you think?
I think they're all
just pretending.
That's all a grown-up is.
Then I just wish it would happen faster.
Because it's too much.
Learning to be a mom, a wife,
and an adult all at once.
I just don't understand…
why everything has to be so hard.
Hold me.
Pat my back.
♪ Hush, little baby
Don't say a word ♪
♪ Mama's gonna buy you a mockingbird ♪
♪ And if that mockingbird don't sing ♪
♪ Mama's gonna buy you a diamond ring ♪
♪ And if that diamond ring is brass ♪
Ae-sun.
Wake up, dear.
Were you losing sleep
because you didn't give me the ring?
Careful. Watch your leg, all right?
My husband's right there.
Hey, don't take that out.
If you gave us your savings,
I'd never forgive myself.
Buy a boat.
I'm sorry?
Buy a boat,
and don't say a word.
If they ask where you got the money,
say you won the lottery.
- Did… did you steal this?
- It's mine.
It's the money from my gukbap stand
before the war.
You've kept it this entire time?
My grandson would have gambled it
all away long ago if I hadn't.
So you hid it to give it to me?
Your mother made me promise.
She said this would make us even.
Huh?
She has to live. She has to.
What will happen to
her poor little children?
Mother.
Mother, can we go somewhere together?
I'm a little scared.
FOREVER YOUNG STUDIO
Didn't I buy this for you
when you got married?
You know, this outfit
is still the best one I have.
I guess it's because of
the dangers of the job.
But we haenyeos are very superstitious.
We believe when we take a photo,
that photo will be used for our funeral.
To think that
I risk my life just for work,
but I still fear death.
I'm afraid to take this picture.
Look at me, dear.
This photo is what
your children will remember you by.
So put on some pink lipstick.
Let's take one for you,
then I'll take one too.
You need to stay alive.
There's plenty of time to join me.
I've outlived my child
for far too long now.
Even after I lost my son,
I still find myself here,
eating three square meals a day.
I promise you
I'll find your precious son.
I'll stay by his side in the afterlife.
I won't look for a new guy.
If you see Han-gyu before I do,
just tell him I'm sorry.
Tell him his mom is so sorry.
Please tell him so.
Please tell him.
I'll make sure
he hears that loud and clear.
But in the meantime,
Han-gyu's daughter needs you.
Watch over Ae-sun like
you'd watch over Han-gyu.
I see.
So that's why you have brought me here.
You couldn't leave that child on her own.
She'll become an orphan,
and she's only ten years old.
She needs someone
to rely on in this world.
Me and my misfortune.
First, I lost my son, and now you.
She is thoughtful, and
she won't be a bother to you.
But if the day comes
when she seeks you out,
after trying her best
to… to stand on her own feet,
it's because
life has been unbearably hard.
I'm asking you to help her.
That girl can withstand
any kind of storm.
But if she says…
"…Please, Grandma, I need some help,"
then you give it to her
as you would have given it to Han-gyu.
That's all I ask. Just one time.
Help her that one time.
You wouldn't owe Han-gyu a thing,
and there'd be nothing
for you to be sorry for.
Oh, sweetheart.
I'll always be her grandma.
But you have so little time left.
Why waste it on me?
I can't die just yet.
I can't go yet.
My dear.
You go in peace.
Go in peace.
Here we go.
One, two, three.
Grandma?
When I'm a grandma,
will I miss her any less, you think?
No, my child. You won't.
The longer you live,
the more you understand
what your parents went through
to keep their children in their hearts.
When your parents die,
you let them go into the afterlife,
but when your children die,
you keep them alive in your heart.
You can't let them go.
You keep them in here.
So go ahead, just take the money.
I'm giving it to my son
when I give it to you.
I'll make you proud.
I promise you I'll live a good life.
We'll make you proud.
That's all I could've wanted.
A MIDSUMMER NIGHT'S FULL NETS
Allow me
to introduce Captain Yang!
I wish all your days
could be as wonderful as this one!
That's my son.
Captain Yang!
Don't you just love the sound of it?
I know I do. Wow!
There we are.
What a day.
It's the best day of my life.
God of the seas,
may this ship not follow the fish,
but may the fish follow the ship.
May its nets always come back full!
May its nets
always come back full!
- May its nets always come back full!
- Nice and full!
Nice and full!
To the gods.
It's nice.
Just as long as it stays afloat.
Oh, Captain Yang.
Here, give me a bowl of makgeolli.
- Well, what are the odds it doesn't?
- Whoo!
How can that woman
make such a fool of herself?
Whoo! All right!
Captain Yang!
When my son, Gwan-sik, was born,
the fortune teller said she saw him
with two sheds full of food!
Now look at him, Captain Yang!
♪ Captain Yang, Captain Yang ♪
♪ Captain Yang ♪
Oh yeah!
What's with that face?
Oh, please,
you know exactly what this is for.
So Jong-gu turned up, eh?
And you're jealous.
You're his grandmother.
You tell my grandson,
if he ever shows his face again,
I'll report that brat
to the police for stealing.
Come on, Jong-gu is still
your eldest grandchild.
He'll perform
the ancestral rites after you pass.
- He'll restore our fortunes.
- Ae-sun will do that.
- She's my eldest son's daughter.
- ♪ Captain Yang, Captain Yang ♪
Listen up, everyone.
I have something to say!
After four generations of the Yang family,
my eldest son is Jeju's newest captain!
Let's hear it for the Yangs!
Yeah!
I think you meant
the eldest daughter of the Ohs.
Because, after all,
it was my grandmother who bought the boat.
I think the two sheds
in Gwan-sik's fortune
must have been about me after all.
All right, you're the blessing.
I admit it.
- And what a big pile of blessings she is!
- Oh, is that right?
Then you know what to do.
Carry that pile on your back.
Weren't you just complaining
how you took her in
without so much as a silver spoon?
Perhaps this boat
will change your tune, eh?
- Yes, it will.
- Ae-sun. Ae-sun.
What an honorable daughter-in-law she is!
The best daughter-in-law in the world!
Who bought him that boat again? Who?
- You!
- You did!
You'd die for that girl?
Look how happy she is, my daughter-in-law.
Hey, Dad?
Look.
- Isn't she the funniest girl in the world?
- Everybody, sing it with me.
Oh Ae-sun! Oh Ae-sun!
During that season,
they stood tall like forest trees.
It was the beginning of a summer
they'd never forget.
Is she okay?
Mom, you're peeing.
Oh no.
It's way too early.
Ae-sun.
- Honey! Aah!
- Take her to the hospital!
- The baby's coming. The baby's coming.
- Honey, please! It's coming!
- What's wrong?
- Quick, hurry!
- Take her! Quickly!
- Careful. Careful.
- Easy now.
- Careful.
You were just laughing a second ago!
You were cracking up!
What did you do at my age?
What did you do every day?
Mmm!
You know Gwan-sik made these?
He's practically an expert by now.
The best jeon you ever had!
You always wanted a silver spoon.
Now you finally have one.
You must be so glad. Hmm.
What an honorable grandson,
making all this for the ancestors.
I mean, really,
you couldn't ask for a better one.
So you're really
not gonna come to the ritual?
Mm. He told me "no."
He told you no?
I want to go,
but what can I do?
I can't disobey my husband.
Even if I mention the idea of getting near
your house, he gets furious.
Oh, he's so scary.
My granddaughter-in-law is a cut above
my daughter-in-law, it would seem.
It figures. Gye-ok is a rabbit, after all,
whereas I'm a snake,
and you're a baby tiger.
Oh, come on.
Will you stop calling me a rabbit already?
I can't help when I was born.
There should be years for other animals,
like raccoons, moles, boars.
What? You gonna list animals all day?
Oh!
Daddy!
Here we go.
Hey, you, how was your day?
Give this to Mom.
Well? What do you want?
That's how you greet your mother?
Oh, dear. Why do you carry him
on your back like that?
You'll wake up with back pains
the next day.
Let's see. There's my little grandson.
What'd you come here for?
To bother my wife? Huh?
Are you hanging around here
to make her uncomfortable?
What about me?
Me? Does anyone care if I'm uncomfortable?
Your mom likes me now.
I gave birth to a son.
I made you a captain.
I gave her some silver spoons.
I've even given her
everything she could possibly want.
She couldn't hate me if she wanted to.
That would be strange, wouldn't it?
If she hated me now?
No doubt about it.
My granddaughter-in-law is a cut above
my daughter-in-law. Yup.
I guess that means
my son is better than your son, huh?
Did he have to give them
all our octopus?
What are we supposed to feed the kids?
Where are you off to, then?
Did you get a house of your own?
Yes.
That's right, sir.
We're moving into our own home.
All right.
Go on.
I just wanted to say…
Go on!
Get moving!
Sir, we really, really…
Will you stop talking?
I don't need to hear the words to know.
I just wanted to say--
Crybaby woman!
Pack your bags.
Thank you, sir, for everything.
Might as well wake up the children.
This is too much to eat by ourselves.
We have to cook some pork to celebrate.
Why are we packing?
We know
it's been tough on you here.
It couldn't have been easy
living in that tiny room for so long,
was it?
A family should have its own house.
You told me that when you were six,
you would come up here by yourself and…
Every morning, you'd wake up
and start climbing the hill.
Mommy! Mommy!
Mommy!
Oh, my baby!
Did you walk here all by yourself?
- Yeah.
- Oh, you precious thing.
Mommy! Mommy!
Oh my.
- Mommy! Hey!
- It's so hot. Come here.
Come here, my darling, come here.
It's so hot outside.
Are you all right?
Look here. I made this.
Do you like it?
Oh, look, it's nice,
and on such a hot day.
You did so good.
You did so good, sweetheart.
Hey, Mom!
Hey, Mom, I got a perfect score!
Oh, my goodness, honey! It's so cold!
How did you climb the hill
in this weather?
SPELLING TEST
- A perfect score.
Well done, honey.
You did so well.
You loved coming here to see your mom.
You said whenever you came here,
you could smell her cooking a mile away.
You told me how your mother
dove for abalone every day
so she could buy this house.
We're not renting it?
I saw it for sale.
Now it's ours.
The previous owner is in Busan.
- It's hard for him to manage anyway.
- You mean, there's no lease?
A home of our own.
I never had a home before, not…
not even once.
Even the conches and crabs
have a place they call their own.
But I never did.
Not once in my whole life.
My mom's house,
my uncle's house,
even my stepdad's house in Dodong-ri.
None of them…
…none of them were my home.
But this is actually…
It really is…
Honey,
you like it?
Mm-hmm.
I do.
So much.
I'm so happy, Gwan-sik.
Aw.
Next time,
I'll buy us an even bigger house.
But this already feels like a palace.
And because it's mine,
it's even better than a palace.
Yes, it's a little low.
Summer is the season of nurturing.
My parents had so much fun going from
a one-bedroom apartment to a proper house
that they didn't mind
expending a little sweat.
Hold on.
I think we need another one there.
Yeah, right there. Put another one.
That's a wardrobe with mother-of-pearl.
Mother-of-pearl from Tongyeong.
It's not secondhand.
It's brand new, and it's all mine.
Geum-myeong.
Do you want it when you get older? Do you?
Yes or no? Huh?
Of course you want it, don't you?
Should we put up a picture?
I think it's tacky. Mm. Should we?
Many years later,
even after they moved
to that apartment with a built-in closet…
Eun-myeong.
…Mom and Dad could never let go
of that mother-of-pearl closet.
Here we go.
Okay.
That shiny pearl wardrobe…
Mama-ma!
…would always remind them
of their bright summer days.
The previous family
were renters, all right.
No one takes care of a place
they don't own.
At the very least, they could've
pulled their hair out of the drain.
Were you busy or what, Mom?
You've never shown up
in my dream before, so…
Did you come because we bought this house?
Are you happy?
Are you proud of me?
Your neighbor bought a truck already.
What?
Does he think making babies
is all a husband does?
You're about to give birth,
and he leaves you to go catch squids.
It's the squids that bought this house.
He should've bought a car by now.
That neighbor of yours
has a truck and a license.
Did you just come
to talk about our neighbor?
Are you that jealous of her truck?
It was a big deal for us
to buy the house.
Why do you care so much about cars?
Don't let her take your persimmons.
Some branches of your tree
reach over into her yard.
Make sure she doesn't steal.
Whatever she takes, she has to pay for.
Ae-sun,
just remember,
she has a truck.
She has a truck.
Geum-myeong.
Run next door
to the neighbor's house, okay?
♪ La, da, di, da, da ♪
Whether boys or girls,
let's have two kids and raise them well.
You only had two children, Gye-ok.
Now Ae-sun here has three.
The eldest girl, Geum-myeong,
brought them good fortune.
Now she's been blessed
with two healthy sons.
My granddaughter-in-law is a cut above
my daughter-in-law, indeed.
She's a cut above everything!
I thought you said
Ae-sun wasn't destined to have any boys.
If an ancestor comes to you
in a dream before childbirth,
the child will be a great blessing.
Because of this boy,
Gwan-sik will have full nets.
Mark my words.
This child has been blessed
by his grandma.
You used to say
her mother's ghost haunted her.
Now she's an "ancestor"?
I can see it now.
This little one will do well in life,
setbacks and all.
You said before Ae-sun was destined
for a life of misfortune.
Maybe you're just a…
A what?
A charlatan?
You could be more accurate.
Full nets!
Gwan-sik's boat has full nets!
That little boy is a blessing.
Fish can't leave
your husband's boat alone.
Uh-huh.
The real blessing around here is Ae-sun.
As you can see,
I'm destined for marvelous things.
Yes, you are!
Our democracy has chosen
its representative for the people.
All right, there's no one
against me, is there?
So it's basically unanimous, isn't it?
No need to vote.
President Park Chung-hee,
as the sole candidate,
received 2,577 ayes and one…
You're the chief,
same as you always are.
I nominate Oh Ae-sun for deputy chief.
I second!
I third!
Let her do it!
Aw, no way. I'd never.
You know I'm not interested in politics.
Who's Oh Ae-sun?
- Gwang-rye's daughter.
- Oh, well, if she's Gwang-rye's daughter…
Exactly!
Let her stand for the position.
Let's vote.
Back in school,
she was class vice president.
- Make her deputy chief!
- That's right!
Veto. I veto your request.
The president gets to appoint
his cabinet members all by himself.
You think Rhee Syngman and Chang Myon
were on the same level? Really?
That's pretty tough talk
for someone who ran unopposed.
Well, in any case,
it's campaign standard. Right?
Basic standards are necessary
so not everyone's
mom and their dog run for office.
Excuse me, please,
it's one free cake per person.
- But you have so many.
- I should run for chief instead.
If a dog can run for office,
why can't someone's mom?
W… what'd you say?
Honestly, I never thought of running,
but being someone's deputy,
I don't think I could handle it.
You said yourself
there wouldn't be a vote otherwise.
I think people
should at least have a choice.
That's right!
- Yes!
- That's right, yes!
What have I got to lose? All right.
May the best candidate win.
The girl challenging the village chief
is Gwang-rye's daughter!
You're joking. A woman as village chief?
What? Are you afraid?
Afraid?
Goodness.
How dare you!
If you're not afraid of it, let's vote.
You? You'll run against me?
Ooh.
You wanna run against me, yup?
You?
W… w… what?
I'd let her be deputy chief if I were you.
Don't embarrass yourself
by losing the vote.
I never knew Ae-sun was such a comedian!
A SMALL BALL LAUNCHED BY AE-SUN
Ae-sun gave it her best shot,
and Dodong-ri had
its first female deputy chief.
Hey, come on.
Stop talking and look straight ahead.
Look this way.
Tall people move to the back of the line.
If you're shorter, come up front. Okay?
Hey, come on. Squeeze in. Squeeze in.
One, two.
Hey! Count to three
and then take the picture.
Are you stupid?
All right.
Everyone, look here.
One, two, three.
SOCIAL DANCE CLASS
Shut up. You're coming with me
straight out the front door!
Stop talking and move it! Move!
- I got 'em. Hurry up and take the picture!
- Here come the delinquents now.
Look at 'em. Look at 'em!
Take the picture. Stop talking!
All right,
bring 'em here, right here.
Shut your mouth and sit down.
- Hurry!
- Gather them all like a pile of crap.
- A runner!
- That's enough! You can settle down now.
There's more down there.
We should check. Out of my way.
Check inside.
There has to be a few more.
Hey, is someone in there? Move aside.
Wait, hey!
That's the ladies' room, you weirdo.
You little brat.
How dare you call me a weirdo!
The ladies' room is my jurisdiction.
You have a crush on me or what?
Why do you always show up everywhere I go?
Just go away.
Go live somewhere else on the island.
What? You still think of me?
Second thoughts?
Hey, why'd you pinch your nose?
Why'd you pinch your nose?
I was talking to you, you brat!
Come on out.
It's all over now.
You have been surrounded already.
Is someone in there or not?
Huh?
Those feet…
The hell with ballroom dancing.
We never needed dancing
to mingle back in my day.
Ever since the New Community Movement,
you people have gotten
way too comfortable.
You think life is one big party every day?
No one would've done this in the war.
Send these go-go dancers
to the Northern border.
You're supposed to count to three.
I already told you so!
I don't believe it.
You're kidding!
What are you doing here?
What are we supposed to do?
What are we supposed to do now?
Fine. This is crazy.
Oh, how do we get you out of here?
Okay, out the window.
Hey, at least cover your faces.
Quick, cover up your daughter's face.
Good idea.
Look at these well-fed women.
They have nothing to do,
so they just go out dancing.
I can't believe this.
You will never face reality
until you're forced to struggle.
You have it too easy. Yeah.
Your lives are just too good.
Dancing will be a real sport someday.
Nice. Real sport, my foot.
If it's a real sport,
why are you covering your faces?
Why don't you show your face
and go to the Olympics? Dancing will be…
Hyeon-suk, wait.
One, two, three!
- One, two, three.
- Dancing will never be a sport.
All right, enough pictures.
- Oh no.
- That woman is fleeing with her child! Ha!
They're like refugees from the war.
Get a picture of her.
Get a picture of that woman!
Get a picture of her!
Don't worry! I'll go get them!
Stop right there!
What the hell?
This was supposed to be my thing.
At least Ae-sun is doing something.
You just tell the photographer
to take a picture,
say cheese, and that's it.
They're going to put you
on the news tonight
for going dancing
with your child for sure.
Are you doing this because you're bored?
Do you have too much money to spend?
If I didn't get to dance
the jitterbug sometimes, I'd go crazy.
I would've killed myself or someone else.
At home, I feel a rage
from deep within myself, Ae-sun.
But when I start dancing,
it all goes away.
So I can't help it.
I keep on dancing.
So your husband, does he still--
He's the same asshole he's always been.
He practically nicknamed me
"How dare you!"
How dare you!
Every day, it's,
"How dare you! How dare you!"
Hyeon-suk learned to say
"How dare you" before "Da-da."
Hey, Mommy, you are Cinderella.
Huh?
You're right.
Well, Cinderella's slipper fell off
because she danced before she ran away.
That makes your dad a prince.
These might work better.
You have to wear something similar
if you don't want them to suspect you.
And who knows?
One of these days, the prince of Dodong-ri
will return your glass slipper.
Tell me. That hairpin.
Did your husband really buy it for you?
That's what everyone says.
They say your husband
spends his money buying you hairpins.
Oh, really?
Uh, this village worries
far too much about my hairpins.
But you have changed, Ae-sun.
They all see it.
You dress better than you did before.
Like you're high-class.
How people dress tends to
reflect how they live.
How dare…
Well, if you're so unhappy,
you should leave him.
It's not like he's some great man.
You shouldn't let him crush you.
Is that why you turned him down?
Huh?
You really don't
have second thoughts?
You have a crush on me or what?
Why do you always show up everywhere I go?
Just go away.
Go live somewhere else on the island.
What?
You still think of me?
Second thoughts?
- Goodbye.
- Thank you.
I have ears, you know.
I heard about everything.
I found out you and my husband
were involved in the past.
What? Is that… is that what they said?
Nothing happened. I swear.
We just… We went on one blind date.
Just once when I was younger back then.
Why did you leave it there?
You should've taken him for yourself.
Then you would've landed
in this pile of crap instead.
Hyeon-suk, never step on a pile of poop.
Instead, you should marry a man
like this lady's husband, okay?
Airplane!
Your handwriting
is much better than mine.
Shouldn't the bookworm do the writing?
Should I get on the boat?
The paint will dry fast.
It's bad luck for women
to get on the boat.
They say the Dragon King will sink it,
and you won't be able to return again.
I don't believe in that.
Stop it, Gwan-sik.
The Dragon King is vengeful.
All the gods are.
Well, I don't believe in any of them.
You, Geum-myeong, Eun-myeong,
Dong-myeong are my gods.
Even in a typhoon,
I'll make it back because of you.
I'll never die.
I'll always come back.
I'll always come back home.
I know you will.
You're my Steelheart after all.
So get in.
You're my blessing, right?
So I need you to write it
to keep our fortunes strong.
Mom always said,
"It's bad luck
if a girl gets on the boat."
But in that moment,
she didn't have the heart to tell me.
She didn't want her daughter
to inherit that kind of world,
so Mom did what she had to.
She challenged the superstition.
I never really believed
in the Dragon King anyway
'cause I believe in myself!
Why should it be bad luck for me
or Geum-myeong to get on the boat?
What? Haven't you heard what's been
going on up here, you stupid old man?
You ever heard about
the New Community Movement?
I thought you said
all the gods were vengeful.
Eun-myeong, Dong-myeong, come here.
Well, I'm vengeful too.
What about the Anti-shamanism Movement?
Heard of that one, have you?
These days, the president himself
arrests people who do rituals for you.
So be nice to me, or else…
or else I won't serve you a bowl
of dried rice during the festivals.
You just eat whatever I cook,
and you're gonna like it.
As if I can't stand in my own boat?
Take that, you weird old man!
Spit at him.
It was
the nurturing season of summer,
and my young parents were growing up.
GEUMEUNDONG
Well,
we have a house
and even a boat.
This is insane.
You happy?
Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
I am, Gwan-sik.
- With the world in their hands…
- Stop.
…the only thing they wanted now
was for their summer to last.
They had no idea
what else summer could bring.
FULL NETS
A MIDSUMMER NIGHT'S FULL NETS
"IN THE HOPE THAT OUR ECHOES
WILL FLOW AND FLOW UNTIL THEY REACH YOU."